Hello, my name is Scott.
And I'm the owner of Climb On indoor rock climbing in Wilmington North Carolina.
Today we're going to discuss the benefits of indoor rock climbing.
Some of the benefits of indoor rock climbing are that you have a controlled environment to learn the skills that it takes to become a good rock climber.
Different skill levels are needed outside when you go climbing.
In an indoor climbing situation you can use many different types of faces, cracks, hand-holds to begin the learning process of climbing.
The controlled environment is a very safe place to work your skills, keep them updated or learn new skills.
Again in a safe controlled environment of an indoor rock climbing gym.
Some of these skills may include knots, how to belay somebody, sport climbing, trad climbing or setting up a top rope in an anchor class.
With these skills you are going to become a better climber outdoors, safer and more knowledgeable.
These are the benefits of indoor rock climbing gyms.
Thank you.